I'm going to have to turn me camera off darlings because I've got a crack in me
grain coming.
So don't worry, that's fine. You can just watch along. See ya. Okay. I think we
'll get started.
Okay, let me just open my camera. Yeah, perfect. Okay well hello everyone and
welcome to my makeup
master class today. So I just want to get started off just by first of all
talking
about skincare and the importance of skincare. So unless you're creating like
the best possible
base you can create for your makeup look or for you know anytime you're wearing
makeup
and it's not going to look so well and a couple of years ago I just thought for
very
badly with my skin and wear loads and loads and loads of makeup to try and
cover it up
and that was the way it's been for it. Whereas now that I've shipped back I've
managed to get
my skin a lot better and I noticed that makeup grows on a lot smoother and so
yeah I always
bear that in mind like the skincare before the makeup is the most important
thing really it's
having the perfected skin underneath. So I just want to speak about a couple of
skincare
recommendations that I recommend and I think for most women to use these
products they're
really going to work for you and yeah so then it's probably good as well so I
'll just read
and Mel's commentary of drink lots of water. Yes like this is the main main
main main thing
about the skincare. These are people don't realise drinking water is that how
huge part of the
skincare routine because it hydrates your skin and you know pumps it out and it
's not going to be
dehydrated and dry like drinking a lot of water it's going to do your skin
wonders so that's like
a top top skincare tip and but then other things that you can use on your skin.
I wanted to show
you a couple of things. I think it's good to consult with like a skincare
expert and
I actually went to just one session with a girl and she looked at my skin on
your microscope
and stuff and told me exactly what I needed and I think it's good for each
individual person to
do that or do something similar to your own research because obviously I'm
going to need
different things but I think a couple of staples that most of the web bar most
in types is first
of all a vitamin C so this is what I use. It doesn't really matter if you could
use any
kinds of vitamin C and you can get really cheap ones from the ordinary skincare
brand. It's amazing.
I used I used them quite a lot and it's super cheap and yet the vitamin C is
very good for your
skin as it's an antioxidant. It protects the skincare cells from damaging
itself due to UV
exposure so all the exposure to UV even in England is like you're still getting
it a lot
so this helps with the UV exposure that your skin gets. It helps with hyperpig
mentation as well
so if you have brown spots around the skin or even lighter spots or discol
oration it helps even
off the skin tone and it enhances radiance as well and since using a vitamin C
this year
I've noticed my skin just so much more radiant and glowy. I have to face one I
'm going to recommend
I'm just going to recommend two products that I think that would really work
and the second
is a hyaluronic acid. This is the one that I use from the ordinary. It's super
super cheap and it
lasts a super super long time and I actually use this for a maple base as well
which we want to
use for our base for our makeup so it's like a multi-purpose in product. It's I
think it's maybe
like a pound for this bottle and that's probably going to last me like maybe
six months so you know
you get a lot of them yourself today. Hyaluronic acid is good for the skin
because it helps
the skin retain moisture and the more moisturizing plumpule skin is the more
youthful it's going to
look and it also helps with fine lines as well and wrinkles and so obviously
you know a very great
thing to implement into the skin care routine. I think when I put it on I feel
like my skin is
like starting to tighten as soon as I put it on but not a tight way to sew it
just
it's like lifting tightness and I like that. It's almost like it's keeping me
skin fresh and
youthful but without it being tight it's weird. It still feels plumpable to put
in
put your identity products out highly recommend the ordinary do a great thalab
ana acid what I have
which is really cheap but there's overgrind you can love that but I know they
're one bricks really
well and I think somebody should show it in the chat. And there's one in home
and bargain that
valor uses I think it was a vitamin C sugar that about but yeah you can get
this stuff anywhere
all different price ranges my ones are fairly quite cheap so yeah they're two
things I recommend
okay so now we'll go on to the makeup so now that we know the people are skin
as hydrated and
fresh and youthful as possible and we'll go on to the makeup so first things
first when doing
makeup I always cleanse my face so this is why I asked that if anyone was going
to follow along
to cleanse your face before I think it's very important even if you were ready
because I cleanse
my face this morning and now it was like second p.m. In Thailand where I am so
you know I wouldn't
use your cleanser this time before bed but I still want to cleanse it again
before doing the makeup
just because of all the dirt oils impurities that could go on to your skin
throughout the day
so I always cleanse it before you do your makeup and someone's trying to enter
the room I'm going to
okay there we go so that's a really good thing about using primer and I'm sorry
I'm going to
be a bit lost now I'm going okay so yeah I always cleanse my skin before doing
makeup and then
I will use a primer and like I said earlier I always use this to prime with
which is the ordinary
hyaluronic acid and two benefits of a primer is one it's given you like a clear
canvas to start
your makeup a clear even base and two it's almost like a foot foreman a
protective layer from your
skin to the makeup so it's like the makeup's not directly sitting in your pores
it's sitting on top
of your primer and so that's two really good benefits of using a primer I
always recommend
you someone and like I said you can get them super cheap I use this as a primer
and it's my skincare
so it's got like two purposes and a couple of makeup artists also Tommy the
same trick so I think
that's a good one but I'm also going to show you another primer that you can
use this is for the
girls who maybe um with like more heavy makeup or needs on for longer so if you
're a dancer
say or I don't know you're wearing the club of the night or whatever else or I
don't know if you
just wear makeup for hours on end and you need to last that whole time and a
very good primer to
use you should put it over this it's um the Nivea for men aftershave balm like
the sensitive aftershave
balm and there's this lady called Nihi tutorials who does makeup tutorials she
's very good and if
you're like watching these tutorials you should watch it she's amazing I always
use the watch out and
still do and she uses this Nivea for men aftershave balm for makeup and she sw
ears by it the primer
sorry and she swears by it and says it's literally like the best primer she's
ever used and she's this
you know she's like this makeup photo and she uses this really inexpensive
primer
inexpensive moisturizer as a primer sorry so I'm going to show you a picture of
it now
I'm going to share my screen and show you it because I actually use this one as
in the UK
and I don't have one anymore and I'm thinking I want to get one shipped over
because it's the best
it's like glue like the makeup it literally like keep it because I used to use
it and I remember
me facers would not move online it's like when I'd be our party and like you
know all heavy
makeup it just wouldn't move if it's one budge it was great so let me just show
you how it looks
one sec let me share my screen and then we're going to get to it I promise I
just think these
are really important tips because effecting the base is more like super
important because if
you're putting makeup onto a base that's oily or dirty or not ready for the
makeup it's just
going to slide off and not look it's best and not hold it's best and I'm not
sure how to
stitch so the screen is already one moment oh I don't remember girls I'm sorry
I don't know how
to share my screen okay I'm not sure how to stitch share the screen but what I
'll do is I'll
just send the picture in the group afterwards um of the of the primer because I
'm very I'm very
confiding oh she's screaming okay perfect shake okay so can you see my screen
now
so what can you do the forms off if you can see it yeah perfect okay so this is
it this is
the product that I really recommend for makeup primer that's going to keep your
makeup on all
night as you can see there it's a sensitive it's a sensitive skin so it should
work on those skin
types and it's got no alcohol into it's not going to be aggressive on the skin
and it's only £2.67
for a hundred mils so it lasts a long time so that's that okay so stop sharing
there we go
okay cool okay so now we'll go on to the makeup application so first of all I
when I like to
find makeup is um I use a foundation I do my foundation first people do
different things first
do the eyes face or the contour face or the eyebrows I just like to do it this
way and
and you can find you know you can try different ways but if this isn't for you
maybe if you're
just trying it this time see how you feel about it but this is out in this
still I do mine anyway okay
so with the foundation I always like to as well and just before I do the
foundation actually
is put on a little bit of cream or liquid highlighter in the high colour see
face because you
basically want to highlight um the high points and then you contour the the
points that are
favored away from the face so we're going to a little bit more detail about
this in a moment
but um so first of all I'm just going to use a cream slash liquid highlighter
this is the one
I use um it's called banana bright face primer by um I'm not really sure how
this has been off that thought this is how it was by um and yeah I just got a
little bit on my face
so I just use my fingers for this and I've just been bit by a musky so
everybody's on
your face right before filming this like before having to do this I'm like ah
what are the odds
like right there but it's not good and then I just start there here like I don
't want to
really rub it in too much because you wanted to peek through the foundations
you wanted to sit
quite heavy not heavy but you know you want to sit quite um seen on the skin
like it actually
do you want to see it I like to put a little bit on my nose here on the top of
my lip here
because it's good to highlight this part is um off your mouth I feel and that's
all and then
actually with the left over I used to usually rub it here on my chest and on my
collarbone and
on my shoulders that's another good little trick and it just gives you more of
that how
good we look if you like to say you're going out and wearing nice dress or when
you don't come or
whatever it is just highlighting these parts here um look really nice okay so
now after that I take
a beauty blender so the beauty blender honestly I think is the best invention
that came to make up
I don't know what the hell I used to do before using this thing I honestly
think it just gives
the most smooth application I honestly just think that it's like put a medical
invention like I
love them so I always I always wet it first and then squeeze it out and dab the
excess on a towel
so it's still a little bit moist but not the point where it's going to wet the
skin so just dab in
and just dab the product in a little bit more could you I use my fingers before
and not my
aidless smear whereas this will give more of a um an even it'll even it'll
basically okay
so now that's done what I want to foundation and I actually prefer to use more
of a beauty cream
then foundation these days especially being in an hot place it's best to use
something like that
and well again if just what's good for your skin there's a couple of points I
wanted to speak about
when it comes to foundation so you want to make sure you get in the right
foundation for your
skin type I think this is where I was going on for a long time because I had
quite oily skin
I still do my skin is definitely more oily than dry and I was using foundations
that were quite
oily and that's because I didn't know the difference between different types of
foundations
and it just didn't sit on the skin it used to just slip off and slip off and
slip off
so now start to look into things further and um so yeah so you've got more of
an oily skin
you don't want to be using an oily foundation you want one that's more matte
with mattifying
and then on the overhand if your skin is more dry you want to be using a more
oily foundation just
so it's um looking at hydrating on the skin because if you use a matte
foundation or dry skin
it's going to look very cakey so that's just like a brief you know over in
overlook with this
it goes into a lot more detail so it's best to just look at your own skin maybe
once again
go to their skincare specialist or go to any counter any makeup store and they
can tell you
exactly what type of skin you've got and what foundation they recommend so that
's one thing
about you get the right off your skin tight and then also always try and get
the right foundation
for your skin colour I think that was definitely at point in time where people
were wearing like
really dark foundation that didn't match the skin colour um just to like just to
appear darker
but I think it's better to use one more your skin colour and then you've been
dark and you're
skin off with um contour like you can like in doing that way and it looks a lot
more
subtle and you still look like you've got to blow but you're not completely
like orange or you know
a completely different colour to the rest of your body and I know that's just a
super
simple you know thing for sometimes when we do this like I definitely have
foundations in the
pasta when I've looked at I think they just don't match at all just because I
want to look browner
um yeah that's all I have to say okay so we'll go on to the application now
so like I said I'm going to use a BB cream with this one's called a CC cream
actually and this
one's quite light um and it's got factor 50 and as well which is great that's
another thing
the last thing I forgot to mention was thinking and most important is put in
factor 50 on your
skin every single day even in England like even like living there like I'm here
swam in the sun
well well not made love at the moment it's dark at the moment but um even when
you're in England
you get an UV rays by every single day on your skin even when you're indoors
you come through the
window so using a factor 50 on your skin every day is the most important thing
because obviously
the sun like the UV rays it ages the skin and it basically undos all of the way
that your skincare
is doing for you so you could be investing all the skincare very looking after
your skin and if
you're not wearing a factor 50 but at least 30 at least factor 30 there's no
points in the skincare
because your skin is just going to go to shit anyway like the fact honestly
since I started doing
this I actually I actually noticed the difference I feel like my skin is just a
lot clearer like
there's not as much damage on my skin it feels more beautiful um and I love it
a little tip as well
but I actually learned from this I was a lady and I can't remember what it was
but she told me
I tip that I would have wish I got told when I was younger because obviously
when we age our skin
obviously on the face ages and we remember to take care of that and the neck we
kind of remember
then we don't think about the back of our hands so you put a little bit of
factor 50
whatever you've got left when you've done your face put a little bit of the
back of your hands
and keep your hands like full as well because as your age what really shows
aging is your hands
you've obviously skin on your neck and if you're like I said you remember to
protect this usually
and look after day like you tried to with skin care and we're not going to get
scared about your
hands so although you might look before here your hands look you know start age
so yeah that's
just a little tip I learnt and I just remember to do that now okay finally we
're getting on to the
foundation so I'm going to use this CC cream so this is like it's cosmetics and
it's called
your skin book better CC plus so it's a CC cream so CC just stands for colour
corrected
and and it says full coverage cream but it doesn't I don't put that much I don
't feel super full
coverage but you can build it up which is great about it and it's hyaluronic
and anti-agent too
which I like when you have in makeup that has active ingredients in it that
actually help the
skin also and this one I think this one's a little bit expensive but I actually
bought this a long
time ago and it's lasted me a long time so this is what I really like to use if
anyone was interested
and I think it's in shade media we have like medium and dark and I quite like
the fact that
but it sort of just matches to your skin anyway when you put it on I like the
fact you don't have
too much to choose from okay so I just put a little bit on the back of my hand
you come by like makeup
in like little palette to put these on but which probably will be better
because then I'm damaging
the skin every time but this is what I use anyway just like about me hand like
this and I actually
just use my finger to put the foundation on if you want a heavier look you can
use a brush and that'll
you know keep it more precise and in place whereas I just use my finger and
then use the beauty blender
to blend it because I really just like to let my skin show through I don't want
to cover it too
much but that's just how that's how I like to do it but if you like a more full
coverage you can
try that as well too so I just start here and I always put it in and down with
motions
I learnt this often I will make parts as well because we have hair in our face
that you know mainly grows down like the wall cupboards and hairs even if you
can't see them
when you're putting it all you're like putting it into the hair and pushing the
hair really
putting it down if you're keeping it all smoothed out if that makes sense so I
think it just creates
a smooth application basically it's putting it on like this so I always like to
do this now now that
I am a blender so just put a little bit on you know some parts of me face not
all of it yet
and I'll just get a beauty blender and just start to just blend it blend out
like this
because I really only want a dirty light coverage because like I said I don't
want to cover the
skin too much we've already wet on getting the skin you know a nice face that's
why they make it
so we don't really want to cover it we want to let our beauty shine for us I
want to cover
ourselves with too much so I just do it like this cover up my mosquito and bite
I've only just done the top half of my face and I'm going to do the bottom and
the reason why
I didn't put the rest on I'm just letting it sit is because it started to dry
on skin
you want to get it put in place before it dries you've got maybe I don't know
how long
probably like a minute or two to get it all like you know spread across and
then it'll start to dry
and not in that area of your skin and if I kept that on there it might have
been hard to blend
and dry cakey in certain parts and then not in over somewhat not okay
so you put it on and then just blend it with the beauty blender
I'm sure that everyone's got their own way of applying makeup or applying
foundation and stuff
but this is I think this really works when you just want a very even light
coverage when you don't
want anything too heavy if you want anything a bit heavier like I said probably
best to use a brush
and barely place the product on more precise with the brush and then I always
like to blend
down just a little bit into the neck not too far just so it is not a harsh line
and I don't put
any product on the neck I just blend what it is on there beauty blender just
pull it down like
you don't want to pull it down I blended it in I think and then just getting
all the
clothes off the face as well just I just spent some time giving this because I
think creating
the payer fact like one of the payer fact of the most in smooth foundation base
is
like very important I think the main thing about where makeup is you want to
look
radiant and you know your skin to glow and you know I think a lot of people
spend a lot of time
on eye makeup but I think that nail on the skin is like really important
because I used I used to
so I used to spend a lot of time doing eye makeup and barely wanted to do falls
like smokey eyes
and all the rest of it and then I was neglecting how the skin looked and it
just didn't look right
okay so
and oh yeah another thing as well forgot to mention about foundation if you're
looking to buy a new
one and maybe get one from a makeup counter what you can do is you can ask them
to give you a
little sample of whatever it is you want you could just say I want to try it
myself before
a buyer because some of them could be like 50 pounds or even more and you don't
want to spend
that much money on a product that yeah it looks great when it's on you're
straight in the shop
like this but then what about five hours time what about ten hours time how's
it going to hold
upon the skin well they might put it on you and then you might not be able to
put it on you like
that yourself so then it doesn't see just you can ask a little sample and nine
times off the
handle give you one and a little you know in a little um a little shingle where
like in your
shade and then you can take a home and try it but that's something to consider
it's bridging out
on a expensive one because it's been so many times up both and I didn't know
that for us
and do that and you just haven't matched or whatever in what did you just say
you need to do it on time
that's funny yeah I've got to go to one so you could do that okay so now that
we've got all
this plans about we're going to go on to concealer now so I use mainly a liquid
concealer so one of
these ones by NARS but their May believe fit me concealer is actually a perfect
juke for the NARS
creamy concealer as it goes yeah of NARS I don't know yeah NARS wading premium
concealer it's a
perfect juke and it's so much cheaper I just can't get my hands on this stuff
over here that's why
I'm not using it anymore but this is what I use to the May believe fit me
concealer and so I'm
going to use the NARS on today so when I'm doing the concealer and I always
just go into my eyes
like this and I used to really do so much and put it so thick but now not so
much because
I noticed that it sits in my in my lines here in my next smile lines if I put
too much on so I
think it's like less as more and you can always build it up as well if you can
blend this out and
then if we want to add a little bit more we can and I like to go here in the
middle of the forehead
just to because this is this is kind of like highlighting the contour and now
so we're sculpting out the face
and then you can put a little bit here too sorry should be looking at me better
really not in the
lens and see what I'm doing yeah not that low down just here so where your cont
our would go okay
so we're highlighting now I'm going to contour next to contour you can feel it
with your finger
where it should go like do this before you do your foundation trying to get a
feel of where
your cheekbone you know like like if it's like just got your finger underneath
my stinky cheekbone
and that's where your contour is going to go and you want to we've contour I
think what happened on
social media a few years ago of all the videos that went around like you know
the whole contour face
and there was these videos going around these harsh lines on the face and you
know people trying
to recreate that and it's not it doesn't look so great I think you're trying to
create this shadow
you're not trying to create a harsh line so I think less is more with contour
in some of the videos
on Instagram and stopped and that go around my conflict what I've said because
you know you see
the makeup artist and he's really heavy lines on but then you blend them all
perfectly well nine
pounds off a ten it's not going to blend out but you want to be left with like
a line on your face
but it's best to just do little by little so okay going back to the highlight
so the contour
it's just about here so just a little bit underneath just put a tiny little bit
of concealer and that's
going to highlight that area so it'll make the clam truss between the lights
and the dark of the
contour so it'll make it appear even more sculptors I wouldn't usually do this
on a normal day but
this is a bit more of a glam makeup look so just like a small amount like that
and then we're going
to set it apart and leave it so to just intensify it you can put a little bit
down your nose if you like
you want to highlight the centre of your nose and I think that's it that's what
I'll do today
other ways you can do highlight in a contour but this is how I'll go what we'll
go with today
and while I'm on the skin we're not going to blend it yet I said earlier about
if you leave
something on the skin it'll start to dry like that and you want to blend it in
fast and with
foundation you do but with this we don't want to spread it too far we wanted to
really stay in
these areas we wanted to very brighten them areas we don't want to spread it
too far
and because it's super liquidy and if you're using a liquid one that is it can
blend for our
quite easy and then you can't really see what you put it and you know you can't
help the brightness
so much so I'm going to leave it for a couple of minutes I like this I'll make
fast too and
like let it all be tricks like everybody else and just leave it for a couple of
minutes and
it looks better when you blend it out with them so we're going to go into cont
our while we're
waiting for that to set kind of so for contour I like to use a cream or liquid
contour
this is the one I actually thought I'd have to test out when I bought something
and it's from
NARS but like I said you can and it's actually just the concealer the same
thing before it's just
the concealer but in a dark colour and well like I said earlier they may believe
they're really good
you grip and um there's a couple of other ones I think it's very am and they're
quite
they're quite inexpensive also and they do good you grip so I like to use the
liquid one like I said
as I think it's better to use liquid as much as you can rather than powder
because if you just
cake and all of these powders onto your skin it's just going to be super cakey
and you know
cloth or crumbly and just not skin like this is going to sit on the skin more
skin like they're
powered upwards so it's why I can say to use cream um you know cream products
or liquid products when
you can so I just put a little bit onto the back of me hand like so just a
small amount because
it's quite I don't need a lot of this and then I just got a brush like this um
you could maybe
use one like that too maybe even one like this like different kinds of brushes
but I like the
the microfiber brushes when using the hoods this one's on my foot it's years
old now but
I think it's even a fake one like I got it from somewhere I don't think it was
even real
macho it does the job like you don't need super expensive brushes I think like
a macho
macho I fell off the back of the bat or something so I just put it like this
and like you know dab it
in so it's not going to be super harsh as soon as I put it onto the face and
then just wear that
as I said before that line you know the phone sorry you just want to go across
that line and up into
the hair like into the hairline you don't want to forget to do that and stop
you want to bring
it up and it'll look naturally possible because at the end of the day like
obviously we're way
of makeup but we wanted to look just in hands-off you see it looking natural we
don't want
it to look too overdone you know so so just very very gently just swipe it
along like this
you can even like do that little face to help with the carving on your cheeking
and I don't just do the line I do the line and then I blend it out this way so
it's got the
sharp line and it blends like the like the product out we keep that quite sharp
and then blend like
this so you can see it's kind of creates a little bit of a shadow effect we're
going to the other
side with contour you probably want to choose a shade that's two shades dark
and then your foundation
and we've been you know maybe one to two shades just take a look at each
product individually
but one to two shades and same with the concealer you don't want to go too
bright and you don't
go too dark either way you want it to be to be quite similar to the foundation
nothing
above you know a completely different foundation because it'll just look it
will just look overdone
so I do the cheekbones
and I like to do the forehead as well so just I get started here in the hair
line I don't go too
close to begin with although quite close when I'm putting the product on but
then once it's on
I pull it back and I just brush out brush back in any you know just to take any
harsh lines
go start to disappear go just do this so put it on face and then I brush any
extra part of back
I don't put a straight on at the back you don't want to go in your hairline too
much
we also do want to blend it as well
they're same again on the other side
and just like buffing like buffing circle emotions like oh because you
basically just
bronzing up the face of contour you don't have to worry too much about you know
sculpting the face
out perfectly it's more about bronzing it up too I like to come down on the jaw
line as well
it's obviously increase more of that in a carved like carved up jaw like that
yeah it's like a nice to like you know
sleek jaw don't know if that's the way but also it just won't put the face even
more
so on top of that line and then again drag it down into the neck you know don't
just leave
it as a line of blend everything out so you can see that the shadow you can
also see that it's not
too much you know like you can and then final final final things with the cont
our I mean there's
loads of different ways I can see just a kind of hope that this is a big spark
in the moment
maybe in another class we'll do like a more in depth one because you can't tell
your lips and
everything to make them appear larger like it's crazy make contour the shape
your eyes
and finally I just go down just go down the nose I don't like to draw it on
because you see
like videos of people drawing it on really thin and then they blend it out and
it really sculpts
the nose and it looks great but I think I'm going to just do it a bit more like
of a natural
natural look so just just add a bit of colour really a bit of shadow that's also
really doing
it's adding shadow to the face and then what we will do a little bit on the
eyes I like to just
put a little bit yeah just whatever's left on the brush continue I should add a
bit of colour just
because it's kind of like a bit of colour to the face and a bit of dimension to
the eyes
and gives you a bit of a nice face to start your eye makeup on this is not a
little trick that I
learned after it's makeup artist now going like given that because as you can
see it added a bit of
colour to the eye area and it's all the same colours with all the edges on the
skin so it all ties
in together nicely and one more tip about contour and actually is um I left
this thing years ago
it's good to if you're new to contour and you don't really know where where to
do it
and I do have a face chart I'm going to send this later on so you can see what
type of
contour on what's best on each face each same face shape but if general rule
for every face shape
is just a number three so you contour the forehead the cheekbone and then under
in the jaw and obviously up to the chin so just a free on the sides of face
very easily to remember
I know I added on the nose area in the eye area but like I said that's a little
bit more in
in depth but that's just a very basic way to remember it and I used to always
remember it that way
so yeah so the contour is done we'll now move on to blending out the highl
ighter the concealer
sorry which is not another highlighter so first of all we'll do this concealer
here
and when you do the men's I like to kind of use the polter quite tall and do
this with a beauty
blender like basically sculpt out the contour and then blend down like this so
that helps
in quite more of a part like a bit more of a shadow and you can see it can look
a bit harsh
so if it starts to look like that all you need to do is just flip the beauty
blender on the same
same side that you use to apply the foundation so it's a little bit too
foundational and you can
just blend over the line like this and that being sort of diffuses the harsh
line makes it look
more like a shadow and light effect while the men are hotline that's that and I
'll do the other side
and then it looks like and then just to go and do the eyes and the forehead so
I've just linked
up my face and like you know a little bit of pressure but not too much pressure
especially
in the eye area the skin here is very delicate and obviously it's the area I've
started wrinkling
stuff a lot faster and so you really want to be like quite you don't want to be
too harsh in this
area the more stress people to the skin the more it's going to start to start
to age and you know
coconut and stuff like that so just be nice and gentle let me skin what I do it
also as well
for what I was on the beauty blender I just start to open the eyes and it sort
of gives a nice little
base for the foundation just on this part of the eye it's not don't go like you
know all the way
to that part that you already put the finger on then you can see them contour
sorry if you do
it's okay as you can see I'm not super am I'm not super careful and like
precise because I just
like to have the hub blended like I don't like too many harsh lines on the skin
I like to keep it
nice and blended basically but also sculpted at the same time okay so that's
the concealer
blended in and then after that we'll just blend in the contour a little bit
with the beauty blender
so just blend the concealer into the contour so I'll just stuff around here I
just I just like
the dotted round skin basically and just blend out any harsh lines okay so I'm
happy with that
we'll move on to blusher so for blusher I use a liquid blusher like I said
before I like to use
liquid as much as possible when possible because you do have to set with powd
ers and
stuff like that so in I like to stuff like this in a liquid form if I can
so the one I'm using is buying ours in I get them in all different brands but I
bought this one
years ago I still like it's still super full and I actually dropped it once as
well as came out so
it's doing quite good in what you can get you know wanted different brands and
this one's called
orgasm this shade but this is it so you literally need like a millispeel amount
on the back of your hand or wherever you know wherever you want to put it
you should shape it first I forgot to shape it shape it first as well should I
we shaped a
liquid product space really I think so a little bit on the back of your hand
and then I just got
me it wanted me fingers and it needs so much like you don't want to pro-die
back here on
your age trying to dab it down so there's not much on and then just smile and
here on the apples
of your cheeks it's where you want to start oh my god so
so momma said I didn't realise you were there just show me what's as a ghost
and I actually do believe like these things as well so just ignore that so yeah
you just
smile and then just dab it on the apples of your cheeks and I really love this
one it's it's so
um skin like I think it looks like you just got um like you just got rosy che
ats as people are
watching all that but it's not like super super fake look in the colour I think
it's really skin
like which I like and then outside so just keep dabbing it off every time don't
go to
dabbing it on your face when it's still quite wet on your finger because it
might look too harsh
so yeah I just blend this with your fingers like I said no produce
I like to be fingers whenever I can
here we go another little thing to do about it as well a little tip
you can put it on the party face that you usually got some men
it sounds weird but it actually looks like good because it makes your skin look
more
radiant but obviously they don't put so much on so it looks so bad but actually
what I mean
so I usually foreheady aside put like a little bit of moisture and I think it
does make a little
difference I really like it and a little bit on the nose as well like down the
bridge of the nose
just a tiny little amount and I maybe a little bit on the chin to bounce it out
because I think
it just feels like a hobosy youthful look so it's like but not too much of
course
keep main of it on your cheeks and then just the excess in windows of it areas
okay so now we're going to go on to baking it's called and it's basically where
you set your skin
um it's just set like the concealer basically or you know different parts of
skin doesn't
need to just leave the concealer and they call it baking because you leave it
on for some time
and and it's like it makes the skin or I don't know but it just it just looks
great and like I like
polidos so I'm using a translucent powder to do this you can use um press powd
ers as well so
like this is a dress powder here and but I have a translucent one for this I
think a translucent powder
with best for baking this one's really good and but I used to use the Lord of
Mesa translucent
powder this is amazing it's a little bit expensive but I think it makes really
well and it lasts
if it goes go along right but I've run off this one now so I've got this over
one and over here
there's no stores but I can buy any of this stuff by the way that's why I say
if I know I can't
but we're going to be buying there's nothing um like of where I am that is on
this island
but the one that I'm using at the moment is this hourglass one and which is
really nice also it's
very finely milled when looking for a translucent powder you want one that's as
fine as possible
and just so it looks more more skin like and more flawless on the skin if it's
got a lot of
if it's not very fine you're going to be able to see it sitting on the skin
okay so to be
I'm going to be under the eyes where we put our highlighter if the concealer
sorry I'm going to
make a lot of it on to here just sculpt this out a little bit more I get really
as you can see
I get really oily in this area especially now that I'm in a really hot place it
's even worse
so I'll bake this area too and my forehead so this is more just where
everything needs it
um and what everything's going to do is it's just going to set that part of the
skin
so places where you're more oily or places where you want to brighten
so they're like the main the main um reasons why you make really it's the
brighten skin and also
keep it nice and matte it's just too much oil I don't like my skin too matte
but I also don't
like it too oily so this is kind of helps so just get a little bit on the brush
and then just if you're doing it under eyes I always just like to go over one
more time at the
user blender just to blend out we're going to start into any any ears lines and
a little
profile doing it and then while I'm still trying to look up put the in powder
directly underneath
like so show you're like baking it as it's as smooth as possible you know like
it's very smooth
and then you put the powder over you're going to use parts a lot of powder
so just under here I don't really want to go over the liquid highlights that we
put on
underneath I just want to really just do the eyes and upside down try and go
and try and
not put it too much on to that I want to keep that nice and jerry so what do
you want side
there so go down to the nose here
and then under here too
okay and then go on to the inside
so you get really neat to go over like wave contour or on the blusher anything
like that
just in the bits that are like the lightest part of the skin
and I like to do all this area like I said because I get really oily yeah and
then the forehead
so just a middle between the eyebrows and then just in just above that I don't
want to do the
outside with the contour you want to leave her in nice and dark with the cont
our
okay
so now we put the translucent powder on I kind of like set it on the skin I
haven't really
done so too much because now we're going to do the eyes and then when we finish
the eyes
we can just off any dropout and because the translucent powder is on already on
the skin
it shouldn't stick to the concealer anything like that so you can just dust it
straight
off so you don't it's not going to ruin the makeup this is why a lot of people
like to do eyes first
because the dropout can happen but if you're baked underneath usually I put a
lot more
baking for a thicker layer on but I don't have a lot left at the moment so I'm
not going to do
the thickest layer but then you can then you just it off afterwards and it does
stuff any fall off
as well like fall off from the eye makeup so now that we've done that we will
go on to eyes
so when I'm doing eyes I like to do the eyebrows first before applying the eye
makeup
because I feel like the eyebrows really shape the face and it'll change how the
eye makeup is going
to look um you might just super heavy eye makeup and then put your eyebrows on
and then it looks
all too much so you might go to the eyebrows first and then do the eye makeup
according to me
so um for doing the eyebrows I always just get a makeup wipe or cotton a little
q-tip
cotton bud and just wipe off any makeup that's on the eyebrow um just because
like I don't really
have dark eyebrows as it is so I like to just um see them as much as possible
we put makeup on
before put more makeup on I'm sorry I think it's just good to get up any excess
makeup that you
don't need on on the eyebrows as it will affect how it looks it might take your
dark eyebrows and
you put foundation on it might even make them look a bit white and um you know
basically foundation
on them just want to wipe it off if you want to see the hair as much as
possible the eyebrow hair
so I just put it on my finger and I put my nail in it so it's like sharp and
just
and the kinds of my cards the mountain helps me get helps me see how I want
them to look
okay so for eyebrows obviously everyone's gonna do their eyebrows a little bit
differently
so I'm really sure um if it's gonna work for some people or some people it
might
I like to have mine quite um as natural as close to how they look now and you
know make like there
as possible I don't like to draw them on too thick or you know do all extra
hair strokes or
whatever else because I think it just looks a little bit too harsh on my face
and then all the
peoples of like faces suit very strong eyebrows so just do your eyebrows
however you like to do them
um for this look but this is what I'm going to show you I'm going to show you a
more gentle one
and it's all oily and I can't open it so this this is what I'm using today
um it's actually um the Anastasia Beverly Hills eyebrow um dip brow gel so I
got it in a
tester but if you put it in a bloody tester while I was on today I just
realised how much stuff I've
got in testers when when I say I got given it in Sephora as a tester and I
aborted I bought it
afterwards because I was like this is the nation and I'm still using this t
ester all this time
and I've got this month's ago so it lasts a long time and I've got this big one
to use so yeah
this is a good product so that's in Anastasia Beverly Hills dip brow and I'm
using the collab
dark brown I mean my hair's always been super light but I think so dark brown
is actually
very sharp and I'm going to rub that with this what seems to work for me so see
okay so just
pull it out there into a little spoolie thing under just wipe off any excess
product on the
tip of it on here because so many times you'll draw it on and there'll be a
huge clump that's
being on the end so um
so I like to use this alongside one of these little brushes I mean a lot of the
time
in eyelash technician cities or even probably by them really people definitely
come by them
on the internet and stuff and just little eyelash brushes or eyebrow brushes
and I like to use this
alongside with this to brush off the product even more so if it does sit on
quite heavy I can
brush out and hair strokes so I just start maybe towards the middle just very
gently I just stroke
upwards my eyebrows are quite sparse so I want to do add a little bit of colour
but
on coverage but not too much so just very very light and gentle like that's the
the main thing yeah you don't want to do anything too dramatic on the face
I think it's good to keep your face as soft and feminine as possible you don't
want super harsh
lines all the time and that's what looks best anyway and then once I've done
one layer of
this I just go through and brush the eyebrows up and then I'll go back in again
any little bit
I've missed or whatever else but I don't like doing them this way it's super
effortless easy fast
and I think it looks nice it looks more like the actual eyebrows rather than
putting too much
product on and then you can't even see the hair and put like underneath so that
's what I'm doing
and I'll do the opposite now
I think with your eyebrows like probably if you've already got them like shaped
and stuff or you
get them waxed or whatever else if you're doing yourself or pluck them you just
try and get a
good shape before any product and the product just sorts it in emphasize the
shape I don't really
like to change the shape too much when putting product on because I think you
can really tell
when you do that
yeah just nice and leg strokes
yeah I think that'll do
okay
and if you want to you can set them with a brow gel I didn't use to use this
but I was giving this
one like as a present and quite like using it now just to clear just to clear
brow gel you get
a couple of pounds in boots like in like comment that the brand is now but they
're very cheap and
just strokes upwards and outwards so you want to do you want to push them out
you want to kind of create
um the higher like the eyebrows are the more like opening in
the way it is but yeah I just think it's better just to just open the eye more
it opens the face
more up than having them a strong heavy brow nice and light and I'm uplifted I
think looks
looks really well so that just brushes them and just puts the hairs in place
more
it's hard to see this here we go yeah okay so now what else did I make up
so what I like to do is and we're doing a brand we're doing a little bit of a
brown
smokey eye today but just a supernatural one I think like just a wearable one
not for too happy
today but if you're showing them you can do different ones which are good and I
think it's
quite a universe I want to start off with so what do I do in a brown smokey eye
first thing I would
say when whatever you're doing what I make you're doing I always use a
transition shade first so I
always put on a transition shade and a transition shade it's basically um what
you're going to blend
out that I shadow into so for example if you're doing black eye makeup like
black smokey eyes
don't stop by putting the black on first I'll start with a leg brown um
transition shades on
the outside and then you can you blend the black out into that that makes sense
um so as we're doing
a brown smokey eye our transition shade is going to be a light brown I'm going
to use this shade here
which is actually the same shade I'm going to use um to contour with I know we
've already
creamed contoured but in a moment I'm going to set the creamed contour with a
little bit of
powder not more like I said I don't make use a lot of powder I've already got
the colour and the
shadows on the crease I'm just going to set it with the powder basically um but
I'll use the same
shade on the eyes because I think it's nice to use the same shades and stuff
like this because
it ties the whole looking together and it's more of a um it's more weirdable
and more natural
even though it's still made up I think it's more of a natural look so this is
what going to act as
a transition shade like I said I've got a little bit on the brush you can tap
it out as well because
you don't want it easier to add than it is to take away so bear that in mind um
little by little
and then if there's any like um just that looks like a bit of concealer or
something in
a line on the eye here as you can see on that side just just dab it just dab it
in or whatever
you know get it even base before applying it. I'm just going to poke my eye and
I'm just going
to start in the outside corner and very gently gentle like strokes just start
to build up the
colour of the eyeshadow so I wanted to sort of go out and also over into this
corner here
I'm going to create a nice shadow so this is like I said this is a transition
colour
so you want to do this in every time with any any most makeup looks that you're
doing
you'll use a transition colour first because it just makes the blend the process
so much easier.
So just keep building it up until you're happy with how it looks so that needs
to be
and anything too heavy because it's just a transition for like I said.
Like you can see it's so much more than real life than I'm here. I've got maybe
there's a flatter too
white let me see and then go into the other eye so I'll do it slowly there
sorry that's going
way faster than for the just so kind of strokes like this and then round into
the corner and
this is the motion like this basically that's where I want the shadow to be so
this area I'll do
here and then yeah you can sort of see that now.
And what I like to do with the transition colour too if we put on eyeshadow
underneath
which we are today I like to do the transition shade underneath too.
So I'm using a smaller brush sorry earlier I was using a big fluffy brush with
a transition
colour as you can see and now I'm going to use a smaller one for underneath.
So that's the one to the top and that's one underneath just so you can see the
difference.
I'm not very sure what brushes these are but yeah you can just just use a brush
or show it with your car or whatever if you're looking for new ones that can
help with
recommendations if you just ask me what I'm not sure these ones are but yeah
just asking
it out I'll recommend some if you don't have already.
So underneath just not into like you know I'm trying to be too careful with
this I'm just
dragging it underneath a new water line like this and you can see it like adds
a bit of like a
um add the nice shadow.
I'm the same on the other side and I'm still using that contour shade.
It's very very light and natural as you can see but this is good for transition
shade.
And then you can just like bring it up and blend it into that so it all blends
in together.
Okay so now that was done now we'll go onto the eyelid and add some colour.
So I'm just going to use a darker brown but not too dark today and all the
colours I'm using on the
eyes are masks today we'll go for like a matte brown smokey eye so I'm going to
use this one here.
It's just a it's just a dark brown so any dark brown is going to go away
sort of darker than the contour shade.
I'm going to the brush and then I'm using a different brush now I'm using a
flat brush it's
not so fluffy it's more flat and compact so it'll pack the fuller on better.
So I'll put it into my hand and I'll work it in like that just so it's on pat
on the brush
and that helps stop fall out. I never usually get fall out to be honest because
I do these
these steps. I'll probably happen now that I've just said it.
Okay so just close the eye and just pat it on the eyelid.
Don't go too far off just get quite a lot of product just on there just on the
top of the
top of the eyelid here you don't want to go too far because we're going to
blend that in a moment.
I'll do the other side and then we'll blend.
Okay so now that that's on as you can see you can really see the darkness of
that one
and the lightness of that one and there's no blend it's not blended together.
So now we'll take another shade which one I would say in the middle of them too
so not as
light as that one and not as dark as this one except in the middle to tie it
all in together.
So it's very simple to do these looks like they don't need all these different
colours or
different this and that. For the eyeshadows we'll do a smoky eye pair directly
with the
darkest one around the middle then the one a bit lighter and then the
transition shader
to blend it all out so three different colours this is more than real.
You can probably even do it too if you blend it quite a bit but we'll do three
today.
So I'm going to pick another brown like I said that's a little bit.
So I'll turn the one in on the outer corners but I'll go on here actually so I
'm going to use one in
this palette here and where I'm going to do is I've got another brush which is
like a bit of a circle
because now I'm going to buff in and save the motions but it's still it's quite
small
so I can get more of it in besides a placement of a product for example
it's what we use for the transition shades so it's bigger fluffy this one's a
little bit more
compact so again better placement.
So same again put it on the brush into the back of your hand just to make sure
you haven't got
two watches for one and you make up and go to the foundation so and then just
in between
the lights and the door this is where this is going to go it's to help blend it
in together.
I'm going to try to do this as quick as possible because I know that it's being
longer than normal
so I don't want to keep anyone too long but
so just on both sides so then you've got the three different colours so one dark
two bit lighter
and three the lightest.
Okay now that's on we're going to go back to the transition colour and just
blend even more and
this is what important now just blend blend blend until there's no more in
harsh lines.
Until you're happy really until you're happy with how it looks because it's a
smoky eyes
it's all messy blended out and smoky and and also underneath we're going to do
the same
so we're going to use in the second colour up so not the dark as well we're
going to use
one in the middle put that onto the eyes as well very very close to the lash
line so the
brush I'm using now is even smaller and even more compact so it's going to get
even more of a
better placement but it's right onto the lash line
you can sort of just smudge it back and forth
you can maybe like see the difference it just ties the
ties the look in and a lot better when you bring it onto the eye.
And then you can go as far as doing eyeliners as well so to make it even more
darker and
smokling stock you would then maybe do a very dark brown or a black eyeliner.
I think as well like a lot of people use black and ice oats you've blackened it
never forth
like how harsh it looked until I used a dark brown and it gives the same effect
like super
dark in the waterline but it's just not as harsh as a black and I think it
looks really nice
and it really brings out a lot of eye colours as well.
I think the black can sort of be a bit just a bit too dark sometimes.
So once you've done that just take the same issue using under the eye
and just smudge it out and you can go back and use a transition shape to want
like you know
whatever whatever you think just keep blending and smudging until it looks nice
and
blended in then also I decide.
Okay here we go.
And I'm not going to do any eyeliner today but you kind of do like a little
line on top you can use like you know a liquid eyeliner or things like that.
Actually I'll do a little bit what I'll do is I'll use this eyebrow pencil
because like I said I like to use a brown sometimes
and what you do is you can pop it on your hand like this and get it warmed up
so the product then slides onto the skin better so this is not just certain you
know like clean
or whatever but warm it up too so it should help with application.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to draw it on the top of my
on my eyelids sorry very close to the lash line.
You can't really sell so much on here as much but it gives it a good look with
yourself it looks nice
it just kind of finishes it off.
But if you want you can do like a black fling or whatever else but
I don't have any left so if we get the lemons I can't do that.
And then finally when I'm done just get the big fluffy brush again and just you
know just blend
out the edges okay so I'm happy with that.
We're going to mascara now.
So just use whatever mascara and that you have that you love to use.
I like to do that in upper and lower lashes too especially on this look.
If you're doing something a lot more natural then you might not need to do your
lower lashes
for that for me but this love I think it really just ties it in on to that very
nicely.
Okay show them a scarlet like makes a huge difference I think and then here you
can always
put on eyelashes and obviously if you are you know wait quite a while from the
scar is dry
and I always like to put mascara on as well before eyelashes.
I know some people are different with that one so just put that eyelashes
straight on.
But I think it's good to have mascara on face because it just makes it look a
dark hair and also
it's a better like easier to set it on to the lashes that I've got mascara on.
But I'm not going to put lashes on today but you could wear lashes with this
stuff for sure.
So now that the eyes are done I've got a lot of hair on the eye.
We're going to go on to lips and then a few final touches and then we're done.
So when doing the lips I just like to wipe off any makeup or anything that's
already on the lips.
And today we're just going to do like a nude just like a nude pinky lip you can
play around with different things but I think for this look a nude lip looks
nice.
So I'm just going to use this lip liner.
This is called Boldy Bear by Marc.
This one really suits my lip colour.
I like one that helps my lip colour.
So maybe even find one that just looks close to your lip colour.
Yeah so just warm the product up on the back of the hands.
If we did with the eyebrow pencil.
And then if you want to kind of like place them in more like a big lip look
you can overline your lips but just very very slightly because then it can
start to look
you know you can start to tell.
So maybe start underneath here because this is where you want the most product
and the least product on the outside.
So sort of like doing this and then
very gently not from too far.
As you can see it looks quite similar to my lip colour which I like because I
don't
like to wait a lot on my lips.
And then with the corners you can sort of shade them in a little bit and I
think it looks nice.
And then we're going to the top.
So I'm kind of lining them just on the outside of the natural line.
So it's not inside it's not too over the top but it's a little bit out.
I think that that works well.
And you can see it's loads of gentle strokes.
It's not just like gentle strokes.
Build the product up.
And then I'm going to just sort of look and see where it needs more product.
Because I'm not going to use a lipstick I'm just going to use a line at last
so the line is going to act as a lipstick too.
You can just sort of like tap on you know the product in different places.
There's no right or wrong way of doing this.
And then I like using fingers sometimes to blend in.
Well yeah I'm happy with that.
I like it a lot.
Quite natural not too like you know in seeing and like sharp and stuff.
And I'm going to use a lip gloss over.
So this one is by Too Faced and it's called Lip Injection.
This one I wanted to use and I couldn't find it.
But now I found it it's on the side of it.
So this one is by Dior and it's called Lip Maximizer
Hyalovonic Lip Plumper.
I really like this one I think it feels nice on the lips.
And it gives a hug and a bit of a tingle as well.
And makes them clump which I really like.
Okay so just a couple of final touches now and then we're finished.
So we're going to quickly set the contour like I said.
So we've already done the contour so the hard work is on the height of things
we've just set in it.
So it's last drop a dive.
So just the same colour you've formed as dabbing in contour brush.
I'm using an angle brush like this in yeah just use whatever you know we use to
use
and work these ones by good as well if you look at the new one you want.
But dab it on in flip away or tap away any excess product.
And I like this brush because it's the hard diagonal so it's all that sits
under.
We can sort of dab on just a very very small amount.
And then on the forehead pull the hair back.
And this also is warm not my skin so already I look a bit more tan it's a bit
more darker.
So if you want to warm your skin up more you can just put more of this on.
But try not to put too much because it might look a bit overboard.
And yeah so just in the contour areas a little bit darker now as well.
Just just sit in one of the face up really.
Fluffy, circular like a swipe of motion you know it's very light.
And that's cheekbone as well.
Finally we're going to use a little bit of highlighter.
Obviously we already put on the highlighter onto the skin first,
onto the foundation sorry.
And you can actually see you can actually see it which is just good like you
know that shows you
not too much foundation under coverage.
Sort as well what a tiny bit of this of a powdered one.
And I'm just using this one here.
Or you can use whatever you would usually use.
So just a little bit on the brush, get a different brush from before.
And if any brush will do very.
And then tap off and then just very very gently
over the bits that we highlighted.
Put not on the forehead I would say maybe a little bit on the nose.
And then just to top it off.
And I've got a little bit on the eyebrow here because this is going to create
more of an arched
open eye look.
So just going to get a smaller brush for this.
And then just for it.
Just on the outside corner like to basically just under the arch through it
where the eyebrow
the highest just under there and out and don't do it in the centre just towards
the outside.
And I really like how it looks.
And I think it looks nice with this smokey eye as well.
I think it looks really nice with it because it's so Martin and this obviously
is a shimmer.
So yeah that's that.
And final thing we do is set the skin.
So I am using at the moment in the Maria Badescu in facial spray.
I used to use the rose water one which I recommend.
I love that one but I couldn't get behind so I don't want to put a different
one at the moment.
What the rose water's really good or maybe any of them really.
And this isn't actually a maple scent spray or I like this as if what it does
is it restores
the moisture balance skin and all the powder that you put on it kind of takes
away that powder
to be clear and makes your skin, just skin back to life and makes it look more
skin-like.
And a really, really great skin and makeup and setting spray is the Urban Decay
all night spray.
All night long it comes in a purple bottle usually.
I used to use it as amazing.
So if you look like like I said earlier if you're like the type of woman that
wears
quite a lot of makeup and you have to wear it for a long period of time and you
want it best
in a good setting spray the Urban Decay is amazing.
Like I said this one's not actually a setting spray for makeup but it's kind of
acts as one
in a way and if you want to pop a set spray then you know you've got one that's
actually a setting spray not just because this is skin care but it's good for
that too.
So just give it a little shape and then put it here quite far away and just
like spritz it onto these.
And then because you think oh that's going to go wrong you make a bath for it
just me.
And then just fan it or whatever you know just let it drive in and then if
there's some set in
parts where it's a little bit speckly or like you know one little bit of like
square so then like
too much of it basically you can just gently put the beauty blender just gently
pat in any bits
that neatly pat it in. But yes I think we're done so that concludes this makeup
tutorial.
I think I mentioned that if I don't want it to and whatever else but yeah it
was just like super
wearable like brown smoothie eye and I think it would work on those skin types
on those faces
and whatever else. So yeah I hope you'd enjoy ladies and if you just want to do
this again and
there's any sit-in books that you want to do or whatever else just let me know
because I'd be
happy to do it with you. I just today thought I want to do one that would work
for most of you
but that most of you would enjoy doing. So yes thank you for long and hope to
see you again soon.